Thank you .
You won 't believe this , you 've probably heard it before ...
but I 've never known any artists .
- I am not an artist . - Well , what 's all this ?
I do sketches for fashion drawings .
- May I see it ? - Oh , no , it 's not good .
If I let you see it , you might not want to know any artists , ever .
I 'm afraid it would have to be pretty bad to do that . Besides , look :
" Let no one say , and say it to your shame ... "
Irena Dubrovna , is that a Russian name ?
- No , I 'm from Serbia . - Oh , I see .
Would you mind spelling it ?
Want to know how to spell my name ?
- Are you going to write me a letter ? - I 'd like to write you a letter .
- What about ? - I would say in this letter :
" Dear Miss Dubrovna ... " I would say , " Will you have tea with me ? "
In that case , I 'd just have to write you another one . I 'd say ...
Here 's my house .
Perhaps , Mr. Reed , you would like to have tea in my apartment ?
Oh , Miss Dubrovna ...
you make life so simple .
You know ...
I never cease to marvel at what lies behind a brownstone front .
- Well , what 's the matter ? - Nothing .
But you ...
- You looked at me in such a funny way . - I 've never had anyone here .
You 're the first friend I met in America .
Oh , I know lots of people in business .
Editors , secretaries , other sketch artists , you know .
- But you might be my first real friend . - Thank you .
- Nice . - That 's Lalage .
- Lalage ? - The perfume I use . I like it .
Perhaps too well . Maybe I use too much of it , living alone like this .
It 's hard to describe . Not like flowers , exactly . It 's ...
It 's like something warm and living .
What 's that ?
It 's the lions in the zoo . One can hear them here often .
Many people in this building complain . The roaring keeps them awake .
- And you don 't mind it ? - No .
To me , it 's the way the sound of the sea is to others :
Natural and soothing . I like it .
Some nights there is another sound , the panther .
It screams like a woman .
I don 't like that .
Oh , I hadn 't realized how dark it was getting .
I like the dark . It 's friendly .
No , no , keep still , please .
- Are you admiring my statue ? - Not exactly .
- Who 's it supposed to be ? - King John .
Oh , King John , the Magna Carta and all that stuff ?
No . King John of Serbia .
He was a fine king .
He drove the Mamluks out of Serbia and freed the people .
- Well , why have this around ? - Well , perhaps you have in your room ...
a picture of George Washington or Abraham Lincoln .
Well , what does it mean ?
- Why is he ... ? Why is he spearing that cat ? - Oh , it 's not really a cat .
It 's meant to represent the evil ways into which my village had once fallen .
You see , the Mamluks came to Serbia long ago ...
and they made the people slaves .
Well , at first , the people were good ...
and worshipped God in a true Christian way .
But little by little , the people changed .
When King John drove out the Mamluks ...
and came to our village ...
he found dreadful things .
People bowed down to Satan ...
and said their Masses to him .
They had become witches ...
and were evil .
Well , King John put some of them to the sword ...
but some ...
the wisest and the most wicked ...
escaped into the mountains .
Now do you understand ?
Well , I still don 't see what it has to do with you .
Those who escaped , the wicked ones ...
their legend haunts the village where I was born .
Boys who come to tea can 't expect to stay to dinner .
Some other time perhaps .
Tomorrow ?
Well , what time tomorrow ?
Dinner ?
A little more to the left , Harry .
Easy . Just a hair .
- I 'm afraid she 's gonna be all right , Alice . - She 's got what it takes , commodore .
Isn 't it a darling ?
- Where 'd you get it ? - I bought it .
- You 're not going in for cats , are you ? - No , I bought it for a friend .
We arrive at the inescapable conclusion that our Oliver has a girl .
A brilliant deduction , Carver .
- I want to show you something . - A girlfriend ?
- A girl . - Anybody I know ?
Not yet , but I know you 'll like her .
Well , if you like her , she 's okay with me .
- Well , hello . - Look , Irena . I brought you a present .
Why , you little devil .
Oh , it 's all right .
It 's just that cats don 't seem to like me .
Yeah , but this is only a kitten .
It 's very friendly . When I had it in the office ...
Alice , that 's the girl who works in our department ...
it played with her .
Cats just don 't like me .
Oh , I know what we can do .
- You got it at a pet store , didn 't you ? - Yes .
Good . Well , we could exchange it for some other pet .
I 'll get my coat .
- I 'd like to exchange this kitten for a canary . - You 'll have to talk louder .
- What did you say ? - I can 't understand a word you say .
I can 't imagine what ...
Oh , landie , dearie me . I can 't imagine what got into them .
All that caterwauling .
The last time they did that was when an alley cat got in ...
and ate up one of my nice Rice finches .
I wanted to exchange this kitten for a bird .
Why , of course . I have some lovely canaries .
One little lemon-colored fellow with top notes like Caruso .
As peaceful as my dream of heaven .
Shall we go back now and select just which little birdie ?
You go , please , Oliver . You pick the one you like .
I 'd rather stay here .
Of course . I 'll only be a minute .
Animals are ever so psychic .
There are some people who just can 't come in here .
My dear brother 's wife , for instance .
She 's a very nice girl . I have nothing against her ...
but you just should see what happens when she puts her foot inside this place .
The cats particularly . They seem to know .
You can fool everybody , but landie , dearie me , you can 't fool a cat .
They seem to know who 's not right , if you know what I mean .
Here we are . Isn 't he a ducky little angel ?
- This is it . - Thank you .
- What do you think of it ? - Oh , he is sweet .
He will like me very much . You will see .
- I like to be liked . - That ought to be easy . Really easy .
- Irena . - Yes .
- I 've been asleep . - I know .
It couldn 't have been very entertaining for you .
I was watching you .
And that was fun ?
Do you love me , Irena ?
You know I love you , don 't you ?
I 've never kissed you .
Do you know , that 's funny .
- Why ? - Well ...
When people in America are in love , or even think they 're in love ...
they 've usually kissed long ago .
Well ?
Irena , what 's wrong ?
I 've lived in dread of this moment .
I 've never wanted to love you .
I 've stayed away from people ...
I lived alone .
- I never wanted this to happen . - But you just told me you love me .
I do .
I 've fled from the past ...
from things you could never know ...
or understand .
Evil things .
Evil .
Irena ...
you 've told me something of the past .
About King John and the witches in the village ...
and the cat people descended from them .
They 're fairy tales , Irena .
Fairy tales heard in your childhood . Nothing more than that .
They 've nothing to do with you , really .
You 're Irena . You 're here in America .
You 're so normal , you 're in love with me , Oliver Reed , a good , plain Americano .
You 're so normal , you 're gonna marry me ...
and those fairy tales , you can tell them to our children . They 'll love them .
Comitadji .
Oh , Mr. Carver , you should not call a good man that .
But it 's Serbian . I got it from my barber this afternoon .
But you might insult him .
- Comitadji means " thief , " " bandit . " - I 've been double-crossed .
Oliver 's bride seems to be a very nice girl . And a very pretty one too .
Carver tells me she 's a bit odd .
- He 's worried about the marriage . - Nonsense , Irena 's a grand girl .
She and Oliver are going to be very happy together .
I certainly hope so .
- To the bride . - To the bride .
Look at that woman . Isn 't she something ?
Looks like a cat .
Thank you so much for this lovely party , Alice .
I didn 't know there was a Serbian restaurant .
Anything you want to know about this city , ask me .
I know all the unimportant details .
Well , how do you like that ?
What did that woman say to you , darling ?
Well , what did she say ?
Now , wait a minute . It can 't be that serious .
Just one single word .
She greeted me .
She called me sister .
You saw her , Oliver .
- You saw what she looked like . - Oh , the cat people .
She looks like a cat , so she must be one of the cat people . One of King John 's pets .
Irena , you crazy kid .
I know a joke about weddings .
Why would my wedding be a dollar-and-cents wedding , eh ?
All right , why ?
I haven 't a dollar , and me girl hasn 't any sense .
- That 's a corny joke even for you , doc . - Come on , Carver .
What is it , darling ?
I 'm ... I 'm going to beg .
Mrs. Reed .
It 's nice to hear that . Nice .
- I want to be Mrs. Reed . - Well , you are .
But I want to be Mrs. Reed really .
I want to be everything that name means to me .
And I can 't . I can 't .
Oliver ...
be kind , be patient .
Let me have time .
Time to get over that feeling there 's something evil in me .
Darling ...
you can have all the time there is in the world if you want it ...
and all the patience and kindness there 's in me .
Only a little time , Oliver .
I don 't want more than that .
Good night , Irena .
Good night , Oliver .
Well , ain 't seen you here in some time , ma 'am .
I 've been married . I 've been married for almost a month .
That 's what I tell this critter .
Nobody comes to see him when they 're happy . No , sir .
The monkey house and the aviary gets the happy customers .
But he 's beautiful .
No , he ain 't beautiful .
He 's an evil critter , ma 'am .
You read your Bible . In Revelations ...
where the book 's talking about the worst beast of them all .
It says :
" And the beast which I saw ...
was like unto a leopard . "
- Like unto a leopard . - Yes , ma 'am .
Like a leopard , but not a leopard .
I guess that fits this fella .
Yes , it fits him .
Best wishes for your marriage , ma 'am .
Would you like some sherry ?
If you 're determined to mourn that bird , we 'll have a regular wake .
It 's not just because the bird died .
It 's me .
I envy every woman I see on the street .
- They can 't match your little finger . - I envy them .
They are happy . They make their husbands happy .
They lead normal , happy lives .
They 're free .
- Do you know what happened to the bird ? - It died .
It died of fright when I tried to take it in my hand .
All right , the bird was afraid of you . That 's nothing .
I had a rabbit once that hated me ...
yet I grew up to be quite a nice fella .
Oliver .
When I went past the panther 's cage ...
I had to open the box .
I had to throw the bird to him .
Do you understand ? I had to . I had to do it .
That 's what frightens me .
Irena , I 've been trying to kid you out of it .
Maybe that 's wrong .
- I 've tried to ... - No one could have been more gentle ...
or more patient .
I 've tried to make you realize all these stories are so much nonsense .
But now I see it 's not the stories . It 's the fact that you believe them .
We 've got to have help , Irena .
Not that sort of help .
There 's something wrong , and we have to face it in an intelligent way .
We don 't need a King John with fire and sword .
We need someone who can find the reason for your belief and cure it .
That 's what we need .
A psychiatrist .
Oh , find one for me , Oliver .
The best one . The very best one .
You were saying , the cats ...
They torment me .
I wake in the night ...
and the tread of their feet whispers in my brain .
I have no peace ...
for they are in me .
In me .
Hypnosis always tires me .
Some of my patients , too , find it exhausting .
It 's only that I remember nothing .
It 's my duty to remember . I have it all here .
Most interesting .
You told me of your village and the people and their strange beliefs .
I am so ashamed . It must seem so childish .
And the cat women of your village too . You told me of them .
Women who , in jealousy or anger or out of their own corrupt passions ...
can change into great cats , like panthers .
And if one of these women were to fall in love ...
and if her lover were to kiss her , take her into his embrace ...
she would be driven by her own evil to kill him .
That 's what you believe and fear , isn 't it ?
These things are very simple to psychiatrists .
You told me about your childhood .
Perhaps we will find this trouble stems from some early experience .
You said you didn 't know your father .
That he died in some mysterious accident in the forest before your birth .
And because of that , the children teased you and called your mother ...
a witch , a cat woman .
These childhood tragedies are inclined to corrode the soul ...
to leave a canker in the mind .
But we will try to repair the damage .
You 're not to worry .
And what shall I tell my husband ?
Naturally , he is anxious to have some word .
What does one tell a husband ? One tells him nothing .
Alice , it 's so nice to see you .
Hello , darling .
- How did you make out with Louis ? - Louis ?
Dr. Judd .
Alice knows , darling .
Of course . Didn 't I suggest Dr. Judd ? I met him on the commodore 's boat .
The way he goes around kissing hands makes me want to spit cotton .
But I guess he knows all there is to know about psychiatry .
I told Alice . I knew she 'd know some good doctor .
I don 't see why that was necessary .
Sorry . I seem to have put my big foot in it .
I 'm sorry , Irena .
I 'm sure neither Oliver nor I had any notion of offending you .
I 'm dreadfully sorry .
Goodbye , Alice .
- Darling , really , there 's no reason to ... - But , Oliver ...
how can you discuss such things ?
Such intimate things about me ? How much did you tell her ?
You can tell Alice anything . She 's a good egg , she understands anything .
There are some things a woman doesn 't want other women to understand .
Irena .
I woke up . You were gone .
- What 's wrong , darling ? - I couldn 't sleep . I went out .
- Where 'd you go ? - Just walked .
I 'm sorry about this afternoon .
I just didn 't think .
Oliver ...
we should never quarrel .
Never let me feel jealousy or anger .
Whatever is in me is held in , is kept harmless ...
when I am happy .
I 'd turn handsprings , darling .
I 'd dance in the streets to make you happy .
Toward the sheer line .
Sixty-two degrees .
Hey .
I 'm sorry . I must have given you the wrong figure . Let me try again .
Wait , let 's have a cigarette first .
That 's the third wrong figure you 've given me this morning .
Getting careless in my old age .
Something 's on your mind . Anything wrong ?
Nope .
Must be marriage .
Well , in a way , it is .
I 'm worried about Irena .
But I thought she was going to Dr. Judd .
Yeah , that 's what I thought . But I ran into Dr. Judd this morning .
She hasn 't been back since the first visit .
But you told me she seemed so anxious to be cured .
- Apparently not . - I 'm sorry , Ollie .
Must make you very unhappy .
You know , it 's a funny thing .
I 've never been unhappy before .
Things have always gone swell for me . I had a grand time as a kid .
Lots of fun at school ...
and here at the office with you and the commodore and doc .
That 's why I don 't know what to do about all this .
I 've just never been unhappy .
Hey .
Now , wait a minute .
I can 't help it . I just can 't help it .
I can 't bear to see you unhappy .
I love you too darn much , and I don 't care if you do know it , Ollie .
I love you .
I 'm sorry . Forget it .
- There 's Irena , you 're in love with her . - I don 't know .
All this trouble has made me think ...
I don 't know what love really is .
I don 't know ...
- even whether I 'm in love with Irena . - I know what love is .
It 's understanding .
It 's you and me , and let the rest of the world go by .
It 's just the two of us living our lives together , happily and proudly .
No self-torture and no doubt .
It 's enduring and it 's everlasting .
Nothing can change it .
Nothing can change us , Ollie .
That 's what I think love is .
Well ...
that isn 't the way I feel about Irena .
It 's a different feeling .
I 'm drawn to her .
There 's a warmth from her ...
that pulls at me .
I have to watch her when she 's in the room .
I have to touch her when she 's near .
But I don 't really know her .
In many ways , we 're strangers .
You and I ...
we 'll never be strangers .
You forgot your key .
Oh , I 'm always forgetting it . But ain 't no worry in it .
Nobody would want to steal one of them critters .
You resist temptation admirably .
- Temptation ? - The key .
- Why would I want it ? - For many reasons .
There is , in some cases , a psychic need to loose evil upon the world .
And we all of us carry within us a desire for death .
You fear the panther , yet you 're drawn to him again and again .
Couldn 't you turn to him as an instrument of death ?
You didn 't come back to see me Friday , I 've had to come to you .
- Well , how did you know where to find me ? - You told me many things .
Why didn 't you come back ?
I don 't feel you can help me .
You 're very wise , you know a great deal ...
yet when you speak of the soul , you mean the mind .
- And it is not my mind that is troubled . - What a clever girl .
All the psychologists have tried for years to find ...
that subtle difference between mind and soul .
And you found it .
It does seem presumptuous of me , doesn 't it ?
Goodbye , doctor .
Irena .
I 'm worried . What 's happening to us ?
I love you , Oliver .
I know , but people can love ...
and people can still drift apart .
And that 's what I feel is happening to us .
We don 't talk together openly .
- You 're not frank with me . - I 've never lied to you .
I ran into Dr. Judd today .
- You haven 't been back to see him . - He cannot help me .
Well , you won 't let him help you . You won 't let me help you .
You won 't even help yourself .
It 's what I said to Alice this afternoon .
- You 're content to go on as we are ... - Alice .
Oh , I ... I promised you we 'd never quarrel .
Let 's calm down a bit .
I 'll go back to the office .
I 've got some work to do .
Oh , do you wanna go up to the office , Mr. Reed ?
I think I 'll go around to Sally Lunn 's , get a cup of coffee before I get to work .
I 'll be back .
- Hello , Mr. Reed . - Minnie .
Maybe you 'd like some nice chicken gumbo today ?
No , thanks , Minnie .
How about some apple pie and a cup of coffee ?
Yes , sir .
My goodness , don 't nobody like chicken gumbo ?
Hello ?
John Paul Jones , don 't you hate people who do that ?
Good night , John Paul .
Here , Mrs. Agnew , new matchbooks for your collection .
Oh , thank you , Miss Moore .
Chartreuse . Ain 't that elegant ?
Too bad you wasn 't here just a minute ago .
- Mr. Reed looked in . - Oh , where did he go ?
Said he was going around to Sally Lunn 's .
- I 'll see if I can catch him . Good night . - Good night , Miss Moore .
- Could you squeeze the coffee pot for me ? - Hello .
I sure could , only this coffee 's been working so long it 's got muscles .
What are you doing in this part of town at this hour of night ?
Stormy weather .
You 're going to have to solve your problems your own way .
I 'm going to drink up and go home .
I think you 'd better go home too and make it up with Irena .
Alice , you 're very swell .
That 's what makes me dangerous . I 'm the new type of other woman .
- Good night , Minnie . - Good night .
- You cold ? - A cat just walked over my grave .
Don 't you want me to walk you home ?
No , thanks . I 'm a big girl now and I 'm not afraid .
- Well , good night . - Good night .
Climb on , sister . Are you riding with me , or ain 't you ?
- You look as if you 'd seen a ghost . - Did you see it ?
Taxi , lady ?
No , please , don 't . Don 't touch me .
Irena .
I 'm sorry .
I 've been worried to death . I didn 't know where you were . I thought ...
What happened tonight happens in every family .
I was all on edge .
You 've got to understand and you 've got to forgive me .
I forgive you .
- Irena . - What ?
- Are you all right ? - I 'm all right .
To loose evil upon the world .
There is , in some cases , a psychic need to loose evil upon the world .
There is , in some cases , a psychic need , a desire for death .
To loose evil . A desire for death .
A psychic need . The key .
The key .
I 'm afraid this is dull for Irena .
Darling , there are some beautiful moderns upstairs .
- Why don 't you take a look at them . - But I like these little boats .
I want to be with you .
- Don 't send me away . - We 're not sending you away .
We just don 't want you to be bored .
We 'll meet you in the main lobby in an hour .
Ollie , look , a drawing of the Victory .
You know , that 's the last man-of-war with a lateen sail aft .
- Could I have the key to the swimming pool ? - Of course , dearie .
What a darling kitten .
Yeah . It 's one of four . A tabby had them about a month ago .
- Turn the lights out when you 're through . - I won 't forget .
Hello ?
Yeah .
- Just a moment , dearie . Yes ? - Is Miss Moore in ?
She just went downstairs to the swimming pool .
Would it be all right if I went to see her ?
Of course , dearie . Right down them steps there .
Oh , gee , I can 't tonight .
Help !
Gee whiz , Mrs. Hanson .
What is the matter , Alice ?
- Gee whiz , dearie , are you all right ? - It 's nothing .
It was dark down here , and Mrs. Reed coming in unexpectedly frightened me .
I 'm terribly sorry .
No , don 't go . I 'm coming right out .
Sorry to have disturbed you , Alice .
I missed you and Oliver , and I thought you might know where he is .
We waited for you at the museum . You 'll probably find him at home .
If you don 't mind then , I 'll run on .
- Could I have my robe , please ? - Sure .
Gee whiz , honey , it 's torn to ribbons .
Thank you for coming at so late an hour , Dr. Judd .
I phoned you because I 'm troubled . I think you can help me .
How much do you believe about the cat people ?
The cat people ?
- The story Mrs. Reed told me ? - Yes .
I believe , my dear Miss Moore , exactly as I told Mrs. Reed :
The story is a product of her own fear , her own overworked imagination .
What would you say , Dr. Judd , if I were to tell you ...
- that I believe Irena 's story ? - Yes ?
Twice I 've been followed by something that was not human ...
something that attempted to take my life .
I believe that was the cat form of Irena .
But why should she wish to harm you ?
Because I 'm in love with her husband .
My dear Miss Moore ...
this story grows more and more charming .
Simpler too , all the time .
You 're both victims of fear .
Mrs. Reed fears the past , and you fear the present .
Mrs. Reed has a very strong imagination ...
and you have an equally strong conscience .
Dr. Judd , the danger that threatened me was very real .
You disappoint me , Miss Moore .
Here is my robe .
To understand this , I should first have to hear ...
Mrs. Reed 's version of the story myself .
That should be a most interesting interview .
I shouldn 't advise you to see her alone .
Do you think I 'm afraid of so charming a lady ?
Dr. Judd , I know you don 't believe me , but you must be careful .
Oh , you want me to carry some means of protection .
A gun , perhaps , with a silver bullet . Is that what you mean ?
If you are lucky enough to have one .
Of course ...
this isn 't silver .
Good night , Miss Moore .
You say you have lapses of memory for which you cannot account .
They are becoming more frequent , and you 're afraid .
Help me .
I can 't help you . You 're not truthful with me .
But I am . I 've told you everything . I have not lied to you .
Do you sincerely believe that if your husband were to kiss you ...
you would change into a cat and rend him to bits ?
I don 't know . I am only afraid .
And if I were to kiss you ?
I only know that I should not like to be kissed by you .
My dear Mrs. Reed , sometimes in my profession ...
there comes a contest of wills between the doctor and his patient .
Patients are clever . Very clever .
And they can fool the doctor sometimes .
You are very clever .
And perhaps you enjoy this little game you are having with me .
But I shall discover your secret .
Dr. Judd , believe me . I beg you to believe me .
I have no secret . I told you everything . I have not lied to you .
I need your help .
I can 't help you .
But I can warn you .
These hallucinations approach insanity .
This nonsense about Miss Moore at the park and in the swimming pool ...
it 's a deterioration of the mind , escape into fantasy .
And it 's dangerous .
At this moment ...
I could go before a board and have you put away for observation .
You are that close to real insanity .
I can 't help you .
You can only help yourself .
You keep going back to the mad legends of your birthplace .
Forget them .
You surround yourself with cat objects , pictures .
Get rid of them . Lead a normal life .
You know , for the first time you 've really helped me .
Maybe it 's because you interest me .
Oliver .
I went back to Dr. Judd 's office .
I 'm no longer afraid .
Believe me , Irena , I 'd have been the happiest man in the world ...
if you told me that a little while ago .
But things have changed .
I had to learn , maybe through this marriage of ours .
I didn 't want to tell you this ...
but now , you see , I have to .
I love Alice .
Irena , it 's too late .
Too late .
Well , there seems only one decent thing for me to do .
I 'll give you a divorce .
- Believe me , it 's better this way . - Better ?
- Better for whom ? - Irena , I ...
Speak .
You can 't speak .
There 's nothing you can say .
There 's only silence .
But I love silence .
I love loneliness .
And they ... They are in me .
Their strength , warmth .
They 're soft . They 're soft .
- Irena , you 're talking like an insane woman . - Please go .
I want you to go , please .
Go .
Bavarian cream ?
Roquefort ?
And you get the apple pie .
I have pointed out two alternatives , Mr. Reed :
Either have her put away for observation and restraint ...
or have your marriage annulled .
It 's tough for Oliver either way , doctor .
As a psychiatrist , I should recommend that you have her put away .
As your friend , however , I have much more reasonable advice to offer .
I think you should have your marriage annulled .
In that way , you are free of responsibility .
- You two could marry . - And if Irena 's sent away ?
The law is quite explicit . One cannot divorce an insane person .
If she 's not well , I 've got to take care of her .
It 's the only right thing , Ollie .
As you will . I 'll have the commitment papers drawn up ...
and arrange an interview with Mrs. Reed at her apartment tonight .
Shall we say 6 : 00 ?
Let 's not play that .
I don 't think Irena 's coming . We 've waited an hour and a half .
Perhaps it 's useless to wait .
I don 't think she intends coming .
She 's probably walking in the park .
Ollie , let 's get back to the office . We 've had a broken-up day ...
- and there 's lots of work to be done . - Suits me .
How stupid of me , I left my walking stick in the apartment .
- I 'll get it for you . - No , it 's my fault .
Give me the key . I shall only be a moment .
Five and a half .
And ...
one and three-eighths .
And one and three-eighths .
There .
I 'll get it .
Hello ?
They hung up on me .
- That 's funny . - What ?
It happened once before like that .
The telephone rang , and I answered .
There was someone on the other end of the line .
I could almost hear them listening .
And then there was a little click as they hung up the receiver .
That was the night I was followed on the transverse .
Ollie ...
let 's get out of here . I 'm afraid .
That was Irena . I know it was Irena who called .
She could call from downstairs . She may be on her way up now .
Get your things .
The door 's open . We can see to get out into the hall .
I 'll turn out the table lights .
It 's shut now . Just a minute ago , it was open .
It 's locked .
Irena .
Leave us , Irena !
In the name of God , leave us in peace .
Come on .
Let 's go down the stairs .
Don 't , Alice . It 's gone . Everything 's all right . Don 't be afraid .
I 'm not afraid .
Look .
Irena 's perfume . Strong . Sweet .
I need a drink .
- Yes ? - Dr. Judd .
Miss Moore ?
Yes . We 've been trying to get you on the phone , Dr. Judd . I called your hotel .
Yes , I know , that 's what I want to talk about . Are you alone ?
You 'd better leave then . She may be on her way back now .
But she is dangerous , Dr. Judd . I warn you .
Hello ? Hello , Dr. Judd ?
Dr. Judd ?
I think Irena just came in . He hung up on me .
Come on .
We 'll get a taxi .
You 're late , aren 't you ?
I kept my appointment .
You see , I 've never believed your story .
I am not afraid of you .
I take you in my arms .
So little , so soft .
This warm perfume in your hair .
Your body .
Don 't be afraid of me , Irena .
He 's dead .
Mr. Reed . Oh , Mr. Reed .
Oh , don 't worry , Mr. Reed .
Sue Ellen and I phoned the police just as soon as we heard the racket .
Thank you .
Sue Ellen , you know better than that .
You 're not supposed to touch anything until the police get here .
- The sword cane . - Broken . Half of it 's gone .
We 've got to find her . Come on .
She never lied to us .